Dylan Lafont

Email: djlafo@gmail.com Github: github.com/djlafo LinkedIn: LinkedIn

Website: https://dylanlafont.com

I am a full stack engineer of 5 years experience who has played pivotal roles across several teams. I've been a valued and communicative member of every team I've been on, and my core strengths are high output, quick adaptation, and critical thinking. I am coming back to the tech world better than ever after a short sabbatical.

VOLUNTEERING

Bereavement Support at Amedisys Hospice Care

January 2024 - Present

Tasked with bereavement support for families of former hospice patients, as well as tuck-in calls to make sure needs are met.

EMPLOYMENT

Technical Consultant at Perficient

November 2020 - September 2021

CLIENT: Fortune 500 Building Company

- Full stack engineer that completed maintenance, enhancement, design, and new features for the main company website.
- Successfully completed a new client-facing project alone from scratch
- Tech stack consisted of React, Redux, Postgresql, and Ruby on Rails
- Started on maintenance team and then moved up quickly due to good performance to work across 3 teams in parallel: bug fixes, maintenance, and the new feature team
- Implemented features as designed from Figma

CLIENT: Large Tax Preparation Service Provider

- Performed content authoring, component testing, and documentation for a tax preparation help website using **Adobe Experience Manager**.
- Recreated detailed designs (Mobile and Desktop) from Figma in Adobe Experience Manager utilizing custom company AEM components
- Updated legacy content with AEM for quick content creation in time for tax season
- Provided documentation to help future authors develop faster and more accurately with a better understanding

Software Engineer at Wellsky

June 2018 - October 2020

• Full stack engineer that completed analysis, design, development, enhancement, database migration,

testing, DevOps, mentoring, and architecture for the new iteration of ServicePoint in the healthcare domain, the leading Homeless Management Information System (HMIS) while getting feedback from beta testers.

- Tech stack consisted of Polymer (Google front end framework), Ruby on Rails, Redis and PostgreSQL. Previous iteration tech stack consists of Java
- Promoted ahead of schedule due to exceptional performance.
- Solely proposed, designed and implemented major product selling point of user-customizable conditional form logic with UI editor (full Boolean logic w/ nesting)
- Implemented many front and back-end CRUD features across the site to manage client data, user and login system including LDAP
- Played a major team role in architecture planning, design, and implementation including multi-tenant SaaS, microservices, and strangler pattern
- Proposed and implemented DevOps processes (automation with CI/CD with GitLab, cloud services with AWS, kubernetes, terraform, automated testing/linting, etc.)
- Proposed and implemented agile processes such as code reviews, sprints, retrospectives, standups, Fibonacci point values, and scrum poker
- Helped modernize a monolithic legacy product

Associate Software Engineer at Wellsky

March 2017 - June 2018

• No notable responsibility difference from the Software Engineer role

AWARDS

WellSky Engineering Award

2019

EDUCATION

University of Louisiana at Lafayette

Bachelor's in Computer Science

August 2012 - January 2017 3.34 GPA

Post-Baccalaureate

August 2023 - December 2023

PROJECTS

2024 - Personal Website (React and TypeScript)

https://github.com/djlafo/personal-site-2024

Personal website with (more recent) React frontend and typescript

2018 - Personal Website (React and Express.js)

https://github.com/djlafo/my_site_react https://github.com/djlafo/my_site_api_express

Personal website with React frontend and REST Express.js backend hitting a PostgreSQL server.

2016 - Mobile Game (C#)

https://github.com/djlafo/mobilegame

Initial framework of game for mobile devices (Android and iOS)

2016 - P2P Client and Server (Java)

https://github.com/djlafo/p2pclientserver

P2P file sharing system with both client/server architecture and **Chord**.

TECH

Ruby, C#, Java

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript

React, Redux, Google Polymer

Ruby on Rails, Redis, Express.js

SQL, PostgreSQL

AWS (EC2, Linux, S3, CodePipeline, etc)

Kubernetes, Terraform, Docker

Jira, Figma, GitLab, GitLab CI, GitHub

Adobe Experience Manager

Multi-Tenant SaaS (Software as a service)

Microservices

Strangler Pattern